Swapnil V. Lokhande

Email: lokhandeswapnil90@gmaill.com Cell No: +91-7507686049/9423402852

Resume

Synopsis

Bachelors degree in Electrical Engineering, having about 2 years experience in production of Switchgears, Quality Assurance in manufacturing of switchgear products superseded by After sales and services of switchgear products in Crompton Greaves Pvt. Ltd. Having experience in Quality Management System (QMS) for COPQ and In Process Quality Assurance (IPQA).

Professional Experience

From October 2014 to till date

Associate Engineer
After sales and services
Export Marketing
Crompton Greaves Pvt. Ltd.

Nashik

Job profile

- Making spares offers, Indents, SAP entries for chargeable spares requirements and breakdown spares.
- Follow-up with manufacturing, planning & stores for spares execution and coordination with Logistics for timely delivery.
- Raising Performa and service invoices followed by SAP entries and follow ups for collections.
- Registration and acknowledgement of customer complaints
- Responsibility involves the Product Execution.
- Responsible for solving customer's complaints regarding to the in-service Products.
- Organizing and Handling Export Customer inspection.
- Handling of projects related to implementation of Quality Management Systems

From Oct 2013 to Oct 2014

Graduate Apprentices Trainee
In-Process Quality Assurance
Instrument Transformer Division
Crompton Greaves Pvt. Ltd.
Nashik

Job profile

- Responsible for planning & organizing electrical tests as per the IEC norms.
- Responsible for in-process inspection.
- Responsible for quality assurance documentation as per MQP for instrument transformers.
- Test bed rejections & their analysis.
- Test set-up calibration & trouble shooting as per requirement.
- Testing equipments maintenance.
- Handling customer inspections.

Dec 2013 to July 2012

Graduate Apprentices Trainee
Production / R & D.
Instrument Transformer Division
Crompton Greaves Pvt. Ltd.
Nashik

Job Profile

- To understand the nature of Engineering Quality Control work along with discipline and standing order follows.
- To learn, understand and develop hands on practical skills on Production of Switchgear product's quality control.
- Stability studies and complete analysis of Instrument transformer.
- Understanding and following different Regulatory guidelines in day to day Production activities.
- To assist in Establishment of manufacturing process of Capacitor Voltage
 Transformer Using Synthetic Oil, In Process and finished Capacitor Voltage
 Transformer testing.

Research Project Carried Out

"Establishment of manufacturing process for capacitor voltage transformer using synthetic oil"

At Crompton Greaves Ltd Instrument transformer Division, Nashik, under guidance of Mr.Hari Baskar, Dy.Manager. from Dec 2012 to July 2013

Academic Qualifications

Degree	University	Institution	Year	Result (%)
BE Electrical	University of Pune	Sir Visvesvaraya institute of techanology,Nasik	2013	55.20
H.S.C.	State Divisional Board	Pratap collage ,Amalner	2007	58.50
S.S.C.	State Divisional Board	Lokmanya vidyalaya,Amalner	2005	58.40

Exposure to Audits

- Team member of ISO 9000 Audit.
- Team member of various quality initiatives of the plant like Six sigma.

Computer Awareness

- Well acquainted with Computer basics- MS Word, Excel, PowerPoint,
- Handling application software like SAP SD Module and communication tools like Microsoft Outlook

Personal Details

Name: Swapnil Lokhande.

Father's Name: Vasantrao Shamrao Lokhande.

Current address: F-2, Deep Apartment, Sahyadri Nagar,

Near Ambad police station, Nashik (422-010) Maharashtra,

India

Permanent address: 13, Shriram Colony Shirud Naka,

Opp of Sagar Furniture, Amalner, Dist-Jalgaon (425-401)

Nasik-422101, Maharashtra, India

Date of Birth: 22nd Feb 1990

Marital Status: Un-Married

Language Known: English, Hindi and Marathi.

I hereby declare that the above information is true to the best of my knowledge and belief. I Request you to kindly consider my application and provide me an opportunity to serve your organization to the best of my ability.

Swapnil Lokhande.